Meier mss., 1927-2010
Indiana University Digital Library Program
- Writings and speeches, 1955-2009, undated (Box 5)
  - Articles, 1959-2009, undated (Box 6)
    - With Paul Schwarz. (1997, Winter). Building and Maintaining a Culture of Change at CPESS. National Forum: Phi Kappa Phi Journal, volume 77, number 1 (pp. 22-26)., 1 printed
    - ( 1998, Jan.). Can the Odds be Changed? Phi Delta Kappan, volume 79, number 5, (pp. 358-362). Also in ( 1997, June ). Educational Policy, volume 11, number 2 (pp. 194-208). 1995-1998, 3 drafts, 6 printed
    - (1987, June). Central Park East: An Alternative Story. Phi Delta Kappan, volume 68, number 10 (pp. 753-756)., 5 printed
      See also: Articles about Debbie/CPE/CCE-91/92, by Debbie, 1 printed; Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 printed; Writings removed from binder pockets, 1 printed
    - ( 2000). Central Park East and its Graduates (Foreword). In David Bensman, Central Park East and its Graduates, 1998-1999, 1 draft
      Includes one letter from Teachers College Press
    - With Paul Schwarz. ( 1995). Central Park East Secondary School: The Hard Part is Making it Happen. In Michael W. Apple and James A. Beane (Eds.), Democratic Schools (pp. 27-40). 1995-2006, 1 printed, 1 draft for update
    - (1994). Changing Lives (Preface). In Jane Day, Changing Lives (pp. vii-x)., 1 printed
      Includes remarks by Emanuel Pariser
    - (1991, Mar. 4). Choice Can Save Public Education. The Nation, volume 252, number 8 (pp. 253, 266-271)., 4 printed
    - (1992). Choices: A Strategy for Educational Reform. In Pearl Rock Kane (Ed.), Independent Schools, Independent Thinkers (pp. 369-389)., 3 printed
      See also: Articles about Debbie/CPE/CCE-91/92, by Debbie, 1 printed; Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 printed
    - (1968). The Coleman Report. Integrated Education, volume 5, number 6 (pp. 37-45)., 1 printed
    - (2004, Fall). Common Sense. Horace: The Journal of the Coalition of Essential Schools, volume 21, number 1 (pp. 38-39)., 1 printed
    - ( 1999, Sept.). The Company They Keep. American School Board Journal, volume 186, number 9 (pp. 25-26). 1999, undated, 2 drafts, 1 printed
    - (1999, Fall/Winter). A Conversation about Schools with Deborah Meier. Connection: New England's Journal of Higher Education and Economic Development, volume 14, number 3 (pp. 20-23)., 3 printed
    - ( 2004). Creating Schools We Can Trust. In C. Glickman (Ed.), Letters to the Next President. 2003, 2 proofs
    - (2009, May). Democracy at Risk. Educational Leadership, volume 66, number 8 (pp. 45-48)., 1 printed
    - With Diane Ravitch. ( 2006, May 24). Bridging Differences: A Dialogue between Deborah Meier and Diane Ravitch. Education Week, volume 25, number 36 (pp. 36-37, 44). 2006, 3 drafts
    - With Allen Graubard. Does Supporting School Reform Mean that America's Public School System is a Shameful Failure? Undated, 1 draft
    - ( 1999-2000, Dec.-Jan.). Educating a Democracy: Standards and the Future of Public Education. Boston Review, volume 24, number 6 (pp. 4-9). 2000, 3 printed
    - ( 1999-2000, Dec.-Jan.). Educating a Democracy: Standards and the Future of Public Education. Boston Review, volume 24, number 6 (pp. 4-9). 2000, 3 printed (Box 3)
    - Original article by Linda Darling-Hammond. ( 2007, May 21). Evaluating No Child Left Behind (Response). The Nation, volume 284, number 20 (pp. 20-21). 2007, 1 printed (Box 6)
    - (1984, October). Feeding Our Myths: 'To Save Our Schools' Flunks. Commonweal, volume 111 (pp. 536-538)., 1 printed
    - (2000, Feb.). Fiddling with Facts. Brill's Content (pp. 63-64)., 3 printed
    - (1968). From a Harlem School. Dissent, volume 15 (pp. 131-137)., 3 printed
      See also: Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 printed; Writings removed from binder pockets, 1 printed; MacArthur Fellowship; binder of recommendations, resumes, articles, etc., 1 printed
    - (1999, Apr. 20). From Deborah Meier to Ben Lummis, copied to MCAS group (3/18/99). MTA Today (pp. 8-9)., 1 printed (Box 3)
    - Future School Leaders. Undated, 2 proofs (Box 6)
      See also: Articles about Debbie/CPE/CCE-91/92, by Debbie, 1 proof, 1 draft, includes letter from Leo Klagholz of the State of New Jersey Department of Education; Writings removed from binder pockets, 6 printed
    - (1992, Sept. 21). Get the Story Straight: Myths, Lies and Public Schools. The Nation, volume 255, number 8 (p. 271-272). Also in ( 1992, Dec.). OPSTF News (pp. 21-23)., 6 printed
      See also: Articles about Debbie/CPE/CCE-91/92, by Debbie, 1 printed; Writings by Deborah Meier, 2 printed; Writings removed from binder pockets, 1 printed
    - (1999, May 23). Give Parents, Teachers Keys to School Reform. Democrat and Chronicle (p. 23A)., 2 printed
      Includes note from Adam Urbanski
    - ( 1996, October 8). Going Back to School... in Boston. 1996, undated, 2 drafts
    - (1987, Fall). Good Schools are Still Possible. Dissent (pp. 543-549)., 2 printed
    - ( 1997). Habits of Mind: Democratic Values and the Creation of Effective Learning Communities. In Barry S. Kogan (Ed.), Common Schools, Uncommon Futures: A Working Consensus for School Renewal. 1995, undated, 2 drafts
      Includes one letter from Barry Kogan
    - With Ann Cook. (1990, Apr. 27). A Helpful Response. Finance and Reform: Education in New York State (pp. 1-9)., 3 printed
    - (1989, May 31). Helping Young Shun 'Ideals' of Violence. Education Week, volume 8, number 36 (p. 32)., 4 printed
      See also: Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 printed; Oversize 3, folder 1
    - (1999, May 31). Here's the Deal, Mr. Unz. The Nation, volume 268, number 20 (pp. 7-8)., 2 printed
    - (2007, Fall). How Much is Learned When We're Not Looking: The Promise of CES Elementary Schools. Horace: The Journal of the Coalition of Essential Schools, volume 23, number 3 (pp. 2-3, 11)., 1 printed
    - ( 1995, Jan.). How Our Schools Could Be. Phi Delta Kappan, volume 76, number 5 (pp. 369-373). 1995, 1 draft, 1 proof, 2 printed
      Includes a note from Deborah Meier
      See also: Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 printed; Writings removed from binder pockets, 1 printed
    - (1989, Sept. 8). In Education, Small is Sensible. New York Times (p. A25)., 6 printed
    - (2003, Oct.-Nov.) In Good Company. The Boston Review, 1 draft
      Includes correspondence, article by Richard D. Kahlenberg and Bernard Wasow titled Private School Vouchers vs. Public School Choice, article by Kahlenberg titled Remembering Al Shanker
    - (2005, Aug. 28). In Schools We Trust. Boston Globe (pp. 23, 35)., 1 printed
    - Incompetent Testing? Undated, 5 drafts
    - (1970, Spring). Initiating Change: P.S. 144's 'Infant School'. New York City Education (pp. 4-8)., 4 printed (Box 7)
      See also: Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 printed; MacArthur Fellowship; binder of recommendations, resumes, articles, etc., 1 printed
    - With Alfie Kohn. (1998, June 8). It's Difficult and Destructive. Boston Globe., 2 printed
    - (1992, June 17). Just Another False Chase. Education Week (p. 14)., 2 printed
    - (1992, June 17). Just Another False Chase. Education Week (p. 14)., 2 printed (Box 3)
    - (2002, Feb.). Just Let Us Be: The Genesis of a Small Public School. Educational Leadership (pp. 76-79)., 4 printed (Box 7)
    - (1991). The Kindergarten Tradition in the High School. In K. Jervis & C. Montag (Eds.), Progressive Education for the 1990s: Transforming Practice (pp. 135-148). New York: Teachers College Press.
    - (1995, Dec. 25). Large, Impersonal Schools Bad for Learning [response to article by Andrew C. Smith]. Ann Arbor News., 1 printed
      See also: Andrew C. Smith's article
    - (1968, Nov.-Dec.). Learning Not to Learn. Dissent (pp. 540-548)., 4 printed
    - Less is More. Undated, 1 draft
    - ( 1989, Feb. 6). Let's Change the Schoolstructure: Teacher/Parent Management, Control and Accountability. New York City Challenge (pp. 27-29). 1989, undated, 3 drafts, 2 printed
      Includes 1 letter from Deborah Meier to the New York City Challenge editor
      See also: Structural Change is Prerequisite for Real Education Reform
    - The Little Engine that Can't: Asking Our Schools to Carry the Burden of Overcoming America's Social Inequality. Undated, 2 drafts
    - (1991, Sept. 23). The Little Schools that Could. The Nation, volume 253, number 9 (pp. 321, 338-340)., 4 printed
      See also: Articles about Debbie/CPE/CCE-91/92, by Debbie, 1 printed, 1 adapted version titled Up Against the System: The Little Schools That Could, 1991, Oct. 14; Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 adapted version
    - Making Schools Scientific: At What Price? Undated, 1 draft
    - Massachusetts Education Reform and National Standards: Two Possible Sets of Policy Assumptions (pp. 16-18). Undated, 5 copies
      Also titled National Standards: Two Possible Sets of Policy Assumptions
    - (2005, Fall). MAT Program Celebrates Its First Class. Field Notes, volume 1, number 3 (pp. 6-8)., 1 printed
    - (1989, Fall). National Standards for American Education [reply]. Teachers College Record, volume 91, number 1 (pp. 25-27), 1 proof
    - ( 1999). Needed: Thoughtful Research for Thoughtful Schools. In E. C. Lagemann & L. Shulman (Eds.), Issues in Education Research (pp. 63-82). San Francisco: Jossey-Bass. 1998, 1 draft
    - A New Reading of the Class Struggle. In These Times. Undated, 1 printed
    - (1967, Dec.). The New York Teachers' Strike. Midstream (pp. 36-42)., 1 printed
    - No Excuses. Undated, 2 drafts
    - No Politician Left Behind. Undated, 1 draft
    - Notes on an Interesting Occupation. Undated, 6 drafts
      Includes 2 copies of a letter from Deborah Meier to Kathleen Devaney
    - ( 2007). On Patriotism and the Yankees: Lessons Learned from Being a Fan. In J. Westheimer (Ed.), Pledging Allegiance: The Politics of Patriotism in America's Schools (pp. 49-60). 2006, undated, 3 drafts
    - ( 2004, Winter). On Unions and Education. Dissent (pp. 31-35). Also in Teachers' Voice, volume 6, number 8 (pp. 1-2). 2003-2004, 1 draft, 1 proof, 1 printed
      Includes letter from Dissent editor to Deborah Meier
    - ( 2004, Winter). On Unions and Education. Dissent (pp. 31-35). Also in Teachers' Voice, volume 6, number 8 (pp. 1-2). 2003-2004, 1 draft, 1 proof, 1 printed (Box 3)
    - (1992, Winter). From Oregon to New York, Preparing Students. Talk of the Nation., 3 printed (Box 7)
      See also: Articles about Debbie/CPE/CCE-91/92, by Debbie, 1 printed; Writings by Deborah Meier
    - Our Educational Crisis and Theirs. Undated, 1 draft
    - (1996, Spring). Partnerships Between Schools and Universities. On Common Ground, number 6 (p. 27)., 2 printed
    - (1994, Jan.). A Plan Equal to the Task: Creating a National Elementary Schools Network. N.E.S.N. Newsletter (pp. 7-8, 13, 15-16)., 1 printed
      See also: Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 draft
    - (1982, May 26-June 1). Planning to Keep Them in Their Place. In These Times (p. 11)., 2 printed
    - ( 1974, Sept.-Oct.). Poor Readers I. Today's Education, number 63 (pp. 32-36). 1974, 1 draft, 3 printed
      Includes a letter from Gene R. Hawes
    - (2003, Mar.). The Power of Ideas. Principal Leadership, volume 3, number 7 (pp. 16-19)., 3 printed
    - (1996, July-Aug.). The Power of Public Education. New Ground, number 47 (pp. 1, 6-7)., 2 printed
      See also: Debs-Thomas-Harrington Award
    - (2000). Progressive Education in the 21st Century: A Work in Progress. In R. Brandt (Ed.), Education in a New Era (pp. 211-228). Alexandria, VI: ASCD., 2 drafts, 1 printed
    - (1959, Winter). The Public Buys a Ghetto. Anvil., 2 printed
    - ( 2007). Quick Fixes and Student Potential. Profession, volume 1 (pp. 136-140). Undated, 1 draft
    - A Radical Proposal for a Conservative Profession Undated, 1 draft
    - Reactions to A Nation Prepared... The Carnegie Proposals: Problems and Possibilities. Networker (pp. 8-9). Undated, 2 printed
    - (1973, Feb.). Reading Failure and the Tests. (An occasional paper of the Workshop Center for Open Education)., 1 draft, 1 pamphlet, 2 printed
      See also: MacArthur Fellowship; binder of recommendations, resumes, articles, etc., 1 printed
    - Reading Myths and Public Policy. Undated, 2 drafts
    - (1992, Summer). Reinventing Teaching. Teachers College Record, volume 93, number 4 (pp. 595-609)., 4 printed
    - (1966, Sept.-Oct.). A Report from Philadelphia: Head Start or Dead End? Dissent (pp. 489-505)., 6 printed
    - (1985, May). Retaining the Teacher's Perspective in the Principalship. Education and Urban Society, volume 17, number 3 (pp. 302-310)., 4 printed
      See also: Articles about Debbie/CPE/CCE-91/92, by Debbie, 1 printed; Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 printed; Writings removed from binder pockets, 5 printed; MacArthur Fellowship; binder of recommendations, resumes, articles, etc., 2 printed
    - Revitalization of Civil Society (Response to), 1994, 1 draft
      Includes letter from Deborah Meier and article by Michael S. Joyce, The Revitalization of Civil Society in Rethinking Schools
    - ( 1995, Fall). A Revolutionary at Work. Future Teacher (pp. 4-5). 1995, Sept. 25, 1 draft
    - Safe and Sane Testing: A Look at the Alternatives. 1988, undated, 4 original drafts, 4 revised drafts
    - Safety, Violence, and the Manufactured Crisis. (Also titled Safe Schools, Safe Streets). 1995, 7 drafts
      Includes supporting documentation, related articles, and correspondence
    - Safety, Violence, and the Manufactured Crisis. (Also titled Safe Schools, Safe Streets). 1995, 7 drafts (Box 3)
    - (1997, Feb. 17). Saving Public Education. The Nation, volume 264, number 6 (pp. 23-24)., 1 printed (Box 7)
    - ( 1992, Spring). School Days: A Journal. Dissent (pp. 213-220). 1992, 2 printed, 1 draft
    - (2008, Mar.). Schooling for Democracy or for the Workplace? Phi Delta Kappan, volume 89, number 7 (pp. 507-510)., 2 printed
    - (2000, Fall). Schools that Seek Solutions. Hope Magazine, volume 24 (pp. 19-21)., 3 printed
    - Smallness (As in Schools). Undated, 1 draft
    - ( 2004, Summer). Smallness, Autonomy, and Choice: Scaling Up. Educational Horizons, volume 82, number 4 (pp. 290-299). Undated, 1 draft
    - Some Comments on the Latest Solution. Undated, 5 drafts
    - ( 2003, Sept.). So What Does it Take to Build a School for Democracy? Phi Delta Kappan (pp. 15-21). 2003, 2 drafts, 2 printed
      Includes correspondence between Deborah Meier and Phi Delta Kappan's Joel Westheimer
    - (1992, October 25). Some Thoughts on Governance., 1 draft
      See also: Articles about Debbie/CPE/CCE-91/92, by Debbie, 1 draft
    - (2002, Nov.). Standardization versus Standards. Phi Delta Kappan, volume 84, number 3 (pp. 190-198)., 3 printed
    - ( 1999, June 9). Standards Yes, Standardization No. Working Papers for A Public Conversation: Education Reform in Massachusetts (pp. 4-5). 1999, 1 draft, 2 printed
    - Statement on Testing. Undated, 1 draft
    - (2008, Sept.). Strong Schools are Essential for Democracy. Phi Delta Kappan, volume 90, number 1 (pp. 32-33)., 2 printed
    - ( 1989, Feb. 6). Structural Change is Prerequisite for Real Education Reform. New York Teacher. 1989, 2 drafts, 2 printed
      See also: Let's Change the Schoolstructure: Teacher/Parent Management, Control and Accountability
    - (1987, Fall). Success in East Harlem. American Educator, volume 11, number 3 (pp. 34-39)., 3 printed
    - (1996, Dec.). Supposing that…. Phi Delta Kappan, volume 78, number 4 (pp. 271-276)., 1 printed
    - ( 1995, Spring/Summer). A Talk to Teachers. Raising Standards, volume 3, number 1 (pp. 3-9). Also printed in ( 1994). Dissent, volume 41, number 1. 1995, 1 draft, 4 printed
      See also: Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 printed; Writings removed from binder pockets, 2 printed
    - (1987, Aug. 28). Teachers and Their Rulers. Newsday (pp. 72, 74)., 4 printed
      See also: Articles about Debbie/CPE/CCE-91/92, by Debbie, 1 printed; Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 printed; Oversize 3, folder 11
    - Testing, Why is it Still Prevalent? Undated, 2 drafts
    - Thinking Small. 1989, undated, 4 drafts
    - (1993, Spring). Transforming Schools into Powerful Communities. Teachers College Record, volume 94, number 3 (pp. 654-658)., 2 printed; See also: Articles about Debbie/CPE/CCE-91/92, by Debbie, 1 printed; Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 printed
    - The Trouble with Teachers. 1968, 1 draft
    - ( 2006, Fall). Undermining Democracy: 'Compassionate Conservatism' and Democratic Education. Dissent (pp. 71-75). 2006-2008, 1 draft, 2 proofs
      Includes correspondence
    - (1969, Aug./Sept.). The Urban School Crisis: Parents and Teachers at the Crossroads. Midstream (pp. 49-59)., 2 printed
    - ( 2009). What I've Learned. In J. Mintz and C. Ricci (Eds.), Turning Points: 27 Visionaries in Education Tell Their Own Stories. 2008, 1 draft
    - (1996, Sept. 15). What it Takes to Make Schools Matter. Newsday (p. A35)., 1 printed
    - ( 2006). What We've Learned in the Small Schools Movement. In P. Hughes (Ed.), Secondary Education at the Crossroads (pp. 145-148). The Netherlands: Springer. 2006, 2 proofs
    - (2000, Nov. 27). What's Lost When We Focus on MCAS. Boston Globe (p. A15)., 3 printed
    - Why a Kindergarten-12th Grade School? Undated
      See: Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 draft
    - Why Don't They Learn? Reading Problems in our City Elementary Schools. 1960s, 2 drafts
    - ( 1981, Fall). Why Reading Tests Don't Test Reading. Dissent (pp. 457-466). 1981, 5 advance copies, 6 printed
    - ( 1997, Jan. 7). Why Reading Tests Don't Test Reading (Revised). 1997, 3 drafts
    - (2002, Sept./Oct.). Why Save Public Education? Harvard Education Letter, volume 18, number 5 (pp. 1-3)., 3 printed
    - ( 2006, Apr. 2). Why We (Progressives) Should Oppose Federal Control of Schools. 2006, 3 drafts (Box 8)
    - (1999, Aug. 2). You Get What You Pay For. Los Angeles Times (p. A13)., 2 printed (Box 3)
    - (1999, June 19). Your Assignment: Fix New York's Schools. New York Times (p. A15)., 3 printed (Box 8)
    - (1999, June 19). Your Assignment: Fix New York's Schools. New York Times (p. A15)., 3 printed (Box 3)
  - Reviews, 1968-1996, undated (Box 8)
    - (1968, Feb.). The Troubled Schools. Midstream (pp. 67-70). 1968, 1 draft, 2 printed
      Book Reviewed: Kozol, J. (1967). Death at an Early Age: The Destruction of the Hearts and Minds of Negro Children in the Boston Public Schools. Boston: Houghton, Mifflin.
    - Comments on Equality of Educational Opportunity, 1968, undated, 2 drafts
      Book Reviewed: Coleman, J. Equality of Educational Opportunity.
    - (1981, Apr. 24). Books: Three Paths to Education. Commonweal (pp. 244, 246-249)., 1 printed
      Book Reviewed: Benjamin, R. (1981). Making Schools Work: A Reporter's Journey Through Some of America's Most Remarkable Classrooms; and Kozol, J. (1981). On Being a Teacher.
    - (1982, Summer).Untitled. Social Policy, volume 13, number 1 (pp. 61-62)., 3 printed
      Book Reviewed: Simon, J. B. (1982). To Become Somebody: Growing Up Against the Grain of Society. Houghton Mifflin.
    - (1984, Oct. 5). Feeding Our Myths: 'To Save Our Schools' Flunks. Commonweal, volume 111, number 17 (pp. 536-538)., 1 draft, 2 printed
      Work Reviewed: To Save Our Schools, To Save Our Children. (1984). ABC.
    - (1984, Winter). 'Getting Tough' in the Schools: A Critique of the Conservative Prescription. Dissent (pp. 61-70)., 4 printed.
      Book Reviewed: Ravitch, D. (1983). The Troubled Crusade: American Education, 1945-1980. New York: Basic Books.
      Includes Diane Ravitch's response and Meier's counter-response
      See also: Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 copy of Ravitch's response, 1 printed copy of Meier's counter-response; MacArthur Fellowship; binder of recommendations, resumes, articles, etc., 1 printed
    - (1985, May 25). The Wrong Track. The Nation (pp. 626-628). [incomplete copy], 2 printed
      Book Reviewed: Oakes, J. (1985). Keeping Track: How Schools Structure Inequality. Yale University Press.
    - ( 1985, Dec. 28-1986, Jan. 4). The Moral Bypass. The Nation, volume 241, number 22 (pp. 717-723). 1985-1986, 1 draft, 1 proof, 1 printed; Book Reviewed: Bellah, R. N., Madsen, R., Sullivan, W. M., Swidler, A., & Tipton, S. A. (1985). Habits of the Heart: Individualism and Commitment in American Life.
    - Review for The Harvard Law Review, 1986, undated, 11 drafts, several incomplete drafts.
      Book Reviewed: Rebell, M. A. & Block, A. R. (1985). Equality and Education: Federal Civil Rights Enforcement in the New York City School System. Princeton University Press.
      Includes correspondence with The Harvard Law Review.
    - With Florence Miller. (1988, Jan. 9). The Book of Lists. The Nation (pp. 25-27)., 3 printed.
      Book Reviewed: Ravitch, D. & Finn, ca. E., Jr. (1987). What Do Our 17-Year-Olds Know? Harper & Row.
    - (1995, May-June).Untitled. Teacher Magazine (p. 40)., 1 printed (Box 3)
      Book Reviewed: Wasley, P. A. (1994). Stirring the Chalkdust: Tales of Teachers Changing Classroom Practice.
    - (1996, Oct. 28). Schools for Citizenship. The Nation, volume 263, number 13 (pp. 32-38)., 2 printed (Box 8)
      Books Reviewed: Postman, N. (1996). The End of Education: Redefining the Value of School. Knopf.; Duckworth, E. (1996). 'The Having of Wonderful Ideas' and Other Essays on Teaching and Learning. Teachers College Press.; Rose, M. (1996). Possible Lives: The Promise of Public Education in America. Penguin.; Sarason, S. B. (1996). Revisiting 'The Culture of the School and the Problem of Change.' Teachers College Press.
    - Michael Harrington--Reflections and Memories. The Yankee Radical (pp. 9-10). Undated, 1 printed
      Book Reviewed: Isserman, M. (2000). The Other American: The Life of Michael Harrington.
    - Some Observations about Recent Books by School Teachers, Especially James Herndon's 'The Way It's Spozed to Be,' Undated, 2 drafts
      Book Reviewed: Herndon, J. The Way it's Supposed to Be.
  - Letters to the editor and untitled op-ed pieces, 1988-2000, undated (Box 8)
    - Letter to editor of Mother Jones, 1988, Dec. 20, 2 drafts, 1 printed
    - (1989, Aug. 22). Obsession with Test Scores Distorts Education. New York Times (p. A22)., 1 printed (Box 3)
    - (1994, Summer). Not Amateur Social Workers. American Educator. (p. 48) (Box 8)
      See: Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 printed; Writings removed from binder pockets, 2 printed
    - Letter to the editor of the Wall Street Journal, 1995, Jan. 17
      Includes 2 drafts of a proposed op-ed piece by Deborah Meier
    - (1995, Aug. 22). Small is Better. New York Times (p. A14), 1 printed (Box 3)
    - Dear editor, Last weekend's extended coverage comparing New York City with New York State schools was almost useful..., 1997, Jan. 7, 1 draft (Box 8)
    - Letter-to-editor, Tuesday's editorial headline was a puzzler..., 1997, Jan. 14, 1 draft
    - Letter to the editors of the Christian Science Monitor, 1999, May 20, 1 draft
      Includes article by Marjorie Coeyman, Cinderella Education Story Waits for Fairy-Tale Ending, to which the letter responds
    - Letter to the editor of The Nation, 2000, Jan. 10, 1 draft
    - Letter to the editor of the New York Times, 2000, July 15, 1 draft
    - Letter to editor, The lively exchange between Allen Graubard and Richard Rothstein on school reform..., undated, 1 draft
    - Letter to the editor of the New York Times, undated, 1 draft
    - Op Ed-alternate, The crisis in public education is one that the latest wave of test-driven reforms will make worse..., undated, 1 draft
    - Parochial School Mystique, by Karen W. Arenson, Sun., Sept. 22, p. 14, Reply... undated, 1 draft
  - Speeches, 1980-2008, undated (Box 8)
    - Dated Speeches, 1980-2008
      - Graduation speech, 1980
      - Progressive education conference, 1988, Jan. 25, 2 transcripts
        Includes letter
      - Thomas-Debs Address, 1988, May 7, Notecards, notes